Frederico Wieser

 $London,\ UK\cdot contact\text{-fred-wieser@protonmail.com}\cdot GitHub:\ fredericowieser\cdot WebSite:\ Fred\ Wieser$

MISSION STATEMENT

Graduate from a top ranked university, seeking a data and analytics heavy role. Experience includes: developing software at university and work for 5+ years, making data visualisations, creating Machine Learning models, and working back end.

Work Experience & Projects

- Developing microservices and applications used to serve data to millions of global users.
- Part of improving and maintaining a five million line code base, working with 100+ developers.
- Code testing automation, analysing failures and suggesting fixes.
- Monitoring infrastructure with Prometheus and trouble shooting problems.

 $\begin{array}{lll} \textbf{Systems Engineer} & (Google \ Cloud \ Platform, \ SQL, \ Python, \ Linux, \ C/C++) \\ NAAMA & (Laser \ Tattoo \ Removal \ Startup) \\ \end{array} \quad \begin{array}{lll} \textbf{London, UK} \\ \textbf{Jun 2021 - April 2022} \\ \end{array}$

- Programmed an automated report generating application for tracked KPIs, sending weekly reports to management, using Python to compile LaTeX documents and Matplotlib graphs.
- Created a Slack chatbot, on a GCP Linux server, for updating key team members on daily KPIs, using Python and the Slack API.
- Performed optomechanical engineering duties, laser installations, system upgrades and research, working within a Linux system and embedded C.

Imperial College AI Hack (Azure, Keras, Python, Flask) Imperial College London London, UK

Feb 2021 - Mar 2021

• Created a map visualisation web app of predicted prices for housing in Boston using 2 different deep learning models.

Cellular Automata, Simulation Research (Python, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib) London, UK UCL Jan 2020 - April 2020

- Created forest fire simulations inspired by Conway's Game of Life.
- Analysed and created visualisations for a final report.

UCL API Hackathon (Python, Beautiful Soup, Flask) UCL

London, UK

March 2020

• Led a team of 5 using webscraping tools to curate a database of events happening around London relevant to students.

Tutor
Freelance, UCL, Taunton School

London, UK

Sep 2016 - Feb 2021

• Taught Mathematics, Science, English, and Portuguese. Ages ranging from 7 to 20 years.

EDUCATION

University College London

London, UK

BSc Theoretical Physics (2:1)

Sep 2018 - Aug 2022

Subjects Studied: High Performance Computing, Machine Learning, Quantum Mechanics, Relativity, Analysis, Nonlinear Dynamics, Thermodynamics

Taunton School (Academic Scholar)

Somerset, UK

A-Levels: Maths (A*), Further Maths (A), Physics (A), Economics (B)

Sep 2011 - Jun 2018

Prefect, President of Maths Society, Academic Scholars Journal Writer/Editor

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, C, C++, LaTeX, SQL, JavaScript
Tools & Software: Microsoft Office, Linux, Jupyter, HTML/CSS

Interests: Formula 1, Surfing, Chess

Teamwork & Leadership Skills: Communication, Reliability, Attention to Detail

Languages: English (Fluent), Portuguese (Fluent)